Shubham Gulati

Software Engineer • Certified Cloud Architect • 6+ Years Experience • B.Tech & M.Tech in C.S.E.

Waterloo, ON · linkedin.com/in/iamshgulati · shubhamgulati.com

SUMMARY

Shubham is an award-winning Software Engineer with over 6 years of experience at top U.S. and Canadian consulting firms. He has a Master's degree in CSE, certifications in AWS, and specializations in Cloud Computing, and Application Security. Shubham excels at building scalable enterprise solutions using Java, Spring Boot, and Microservices. Apart from his strong experience in Backend technologies, he also has a solid understanding of CI/CD, DevOps, and Frontend technologies, making him well-suited for full-stack application development.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2022-2022

- Led a backend team to enhance the client's usage reporting application, resulting in a 25% improvement in user satisfaction.
- Promoted software engineering best practices, leading to 35% increase in reliability and adherence to high quality standards.
- Conducted training sessions and code reviews for new hires in the team, improving the team's onboarding efficiency by 20%.

Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India – 2019-2022

- ◆ Architected and developed personalized features for a client's Customer Support Portal, increasing user satisfaction by 25%.
- Developed a reusable foundation for all Microservices, enhancing the system reliability and reducing technical debt by 30%.
- ◆ Integrated a Spring Cloud Config Server and HashiCorp Vault for easy management of secrets, reducing security risk by 40%.

Business Technology Analyst, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2018-2019

- Transformed complex HR Portal monolith with 750+ APIs to cloud-native Microservices, improving system scalability by 35%.
- Developed resilient Microservices using Java, Spring Boot, and Spring Cloud, resulting in scalable and maintainable backend.
- Delivered high precision modules like Mergers & Acquisitions and Career Advancement, enhancing system reliability by 20%.

Associate Software Engineer, CGI Inc

ndia - 2016-2018

- Developed RESTful web services with comprehensive unit tests for a client's call and data billing platform for M2M IoT devices.
- ◆ Developed innovative framework to manage state of production system using JMX, reducing maintenance downtime by 95%.
- ◆ Transformed applications from Oracle WebLogic Server to embedded Tomcat Server with Spring Boot, reducing license costs.

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Certificate, Computer Application Security, Conestoga College
Postgraduate Certificate, Cloud Computing & Blockchain, Saskatchewan Polytechnic
Master of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology
Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology

Waterloo, ON – 2024

Saskatoon, SK – 2023

India

ndia

SKILLS

Backend: Java (8 and 11, with lambdas), Spring Boot, Spring Cloud; JUnit, Power Mockito; Node.js; RESTful APIs, Web Services, OpenAPI, Swagger; Microservices, Event-driven Architecture, Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ; ORMs, JDBC, JPA, Hibernate. Database: SQL, NoSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Amazon DynamoDB, PL/SQL. Frontend: React.js (including RSC), JavaScript, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, HTML, CSS. Package Managers: Maven, Gradle, NPM, PNPM. Server: Linux, Ubuntu; Tomcat, Next.js. Cloud: AWS (including VPC, EC2, Lambda, ECS, Fargate, ALB, RDS, DynamoDB, S3, SQS, API Gateway, CloudFormation), GCP, Infrastructure as Code. Orchestration: Docker, Jenkins, GitHub Actions. Logging & Monitoring: Logstash, Elasticsearch, Kibana. Tools: Postman; Git, GitHub; SonarQube; VSCode, IntelliJ IDEA, WebStorm; Jira, Agile/Scrum. Security: HashiCorp Vault, OAuth, JWT; SSH, TLS, CAP, AAA; Software Supply Chain.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

FPDELC1KXFF1QXK5

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

JJMV6422RJ1Q1NWV

HONOURS & AWARDS

Conestoga	- High Distinction Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Computer Application Security.	2024
Conestoga	- Best of Program Award, Best Capstone Project in Computer Application Security program.	2024
Saskpoly	 Dean's List Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Cloud Computing & Blockchain. 	2023
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Technical contribution to the success of the eCX project. 	2022
Deloitte	 Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the STAR Migration project. 	2020
Deloitte	 Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the HRAlly project. 	2019
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Project delivery excellence during the development of the HRAlly project. 	2019
Deloitte	 Spot Award, Critical support during CSP 2.0 project go-live. 	2019
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Delivery excellence during CSP 2.0 project development. 	2018
CGI	 Apex Award, Unsupervised delivery, and individual contribution to the M2M GDSP project. 	2017

PROJECTS

Blog - Built a personal website/blog using React, Typescript, and Next.js, with a CI/CD pipeline using GitHub Actions.
 OSCAR EMR - Contributed to software supply chain security of open-source OSCAR project used in Canadian Healthcare industry.

Emoverse – Built a full-stack journaling platform using AWS serverless services, and fully automated CI/CD pipeline.

SmartDegree - Built a DApp to issue digital certificates using Solidity and Web3 and deployed on Ethereum blockchain.

PUBLICATIONS

Research Paper

- ◆ An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System.
- Published in the IEEE Journal https://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICRITO.2014.7014723